Contact

Avilés, Asturias. Spain +34685583783 (Mobile) Isilva@gmail.com

www.leonelsilva.com (Portfolio)

www.linkedin.com/in/leonelatwork

Main Skills

UX / UI Design

User-centered Design

Interaction Design

UX Research

Wearables Design

Design Patterns

Responsive Web Design

HTML / CSS

Agile Methodologies

SAAS Design

Wireframing

Prototyping

Languages

Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

English (Professional Working)

Certifications

Designing for Neural Networks and Al Interfaces

Design Thinking: Understanding the Process

User Experience Design for Wearables

UX for Voice: Planning and Implementation

Learning Jira Software

Leonel Silva

UX Design & Research Consultant | Leonelsilva.com Asturias - Spain

About

8 years working remotely on UI UX Design, IxD, HCI, Accesibility and Usability on SAAS, mobile apps and websites, experience working on multi-device multi-agents designs.

I can wear multiple hats (of an UX designer, a UI designer and a UI basic developer html+css) with pride and be able to take on each challenge with passion.

I am a digital nomad currently in Spain, all my career I have worked remotely with multidisciplinary teams reporting directly to CTOs, CEOs, Product Owners, Stakeholders, or directly with clients.

Experience in deploying User Centred Design processes and techniques (e.g. personas, scenarios, prototyping, ideation, cocreation).

Passion for design and strong command of visual design capabilities, including composition, layout information hierarchy, typography and color.

Knowledge about css + html and responsive design, I can help to implement my UI Designs or UX improvements in the saas, app or website.

I'm used to work on Agile development environment, expert knowledge of interaction design, information architecture and usercentered design, experienced in establish and promote design guidelines, best practices and standards.

I am also a Graphic Designer and I have knowledge of Branding, Marketing, image & video editing, Typography and Color applied to POP material, signage and publications for social networks.

Experience

Azumo, LLC

UX Specialist sep 2017 - Present

Working remote for USA and Argentina

Design experiences for new and existing products and features, provide efficient and effective graphical solutions that are elegant and scalable, work with dev teams through collaboration tools, work collaboratively with UX team, developers, testers, product owners and managers.

Adhere to quality assurance standards and practices, provide regular status reports on assigned projects, build graphic guidelines, UI storyboards,

Wireframes, basic prototypes, html prototypes, customer journey maps, user flows, task flows, user personas, scenarios and ux storyboards for products. Translate requirements into intuitive, highly functional, and visually stunning digital products.

Monitor the implementation process to ensure that the final product matches the design specifications.

AcuityAds Inc

Senior IxD UX UI Designer sep 2014 - aug 2017 Working remote for Canada

UX & UI Design, Wireframing, Prototyping, Mockups, Front-End Developing with RWD / HTML5 / CSS3.

Apply best practices and personal skill to structure and layout of various digital experiences to achieve the greatest client and user satisfaction.

Neoris

Junior Web Designer jul 2012 - sep 2014 Working remote for USA and Mexico

IA / UX / UI, Wireframing, Mockups, Prototyping and Front-End Developing. Graphic Design, Corporate Identity, video editing and multimedia Presentations.

Wikot

Senior IxD UX UI Designer oct 2011 - jul 2012 Working remote for USA

UX & UI Design, Wireframing, Mockups.

Responsible for UX/UI across mobile, desktop on SAAS, websites and apps.

UX Skills / Metodologies

Information Architecture

User Flows **UI** Storyboard Task Flows IxD Storyboard **UX Personas**

Red Route Analysis

UX Scenarios Lo-Fi y Hi-Fi Wireframes Prototyping

Usability Analysis Accessibility Analysis **Customer Journey Maps** Benchmarking & Competitor

Analysis

UX Storyboard

UI Skills / Metodologies

Interface Design Responsive Web Design HTML

CSS / SASS / LESS **Design Patterns** Atomic Design

Material Design Guidelines Apple Human Interface Guidelines

I can help implementing design styles on React or Angular but I'm not a Front-End Developer.

Visual Design Skills

Branding Logo Design Corporate identity manual Image & Video Edition

Deliverables for print and on-line marketing like Facebook & Google Ads advertises, Flyers, Business cards.

Presentations with Google docs, Powerpoint and simple videos.

Tools

Adobe XD Sketch Balsamiq Figma Invision / Marvel Adobe Suite

Abstract Basecamp Jira / Confluence Harvest Atom / Sublime

Education

Design Institute of Caracas

Bachelor's Degree, UX Design · (2007 - 2011)

José María Vargas University

Bachelor's Degree, Visual Design (2004 - 2007)